Guide to the Amos Niven Wilder and Wilder Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Freedman Dramatic Agency Records, 1909-2011; Series IX
  - Contracts, 1929–2008
    - Our Town materials
      - Czech language agreements
        - Stage production in the Czech Republic typescript agreements (2 copies), 1995 (Box 283, Folder 3690)
        - Stage rights executed copies, 1986–1992 (Box 283, Folder 3691)
        - Production rights, 1978 (Box 283, Folder 3692)
        - First class production rights contract, 1965 (Box 283, Folder 3693)
      - Dutch language rights (2 copies), 1964 (Box 283, Folder 3694)
      - English production in Surrey, England agreements, 2004 (Box 283, Folder 3695)
      - National Theatre of Ireland typescript agreements, 2001 February 22 (Box 283, Folder 3696)
      - National Theatre of Ireland production agreements, 2000 (Box 283, Folder 3697)
      - Island Theatre Company of Ireland production agreement, 1996 (Box 283, Folder 3698)
      - Anglo- American Theatre production agreement and amendments, 1990–1991 (Box 284, Folder 3699)
      - Soulpepper Theatre Company, Toronton Canada typescript agreement (2 copies), 1998 (Box 284, Folder 3700)
      - Scott Morfee and the Barrow Street Theatre production contract, 2008 (Box 284, Folder 3701)
      - British Broadcasting Corporation radio broadcast agreements, 1993–1997 (Box 284, Folder 3702)
      - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation radio broadcast agreement, 1980 (Box 284, Folder 3703)
      - Plumstead Playhouse correspondence and photcopied dramatic sales slip, 1969 (Box 284, Folder 3704)
      - French language stage production in Montreal, Canada, 1988 (Box 284, Folder 3705)
      - National Players, Olney Theatre Center agreement, 2003 (Box 284, Folder 3706)
      - Westport's Own LLC license agreement for Broadway production, 2002 October 15 (Box 284, Folder 3707)
      - Scott Hamilton Kennedy correspondence regarding documentary, 2002 September 19 (Box 284, Folder 3708)
      - Harvard Theatre Collection correspondence, 1988 December 13 (Box 284, Folder 3709)
      - Lincoln Center Theater photocopied production agreement, 1987–1989 (Box 284, Folder 3710)
      - ENA, Estonian Drama Agency, typescript agreement (3 copies), 2003 (Box 284, Folder 3711)
      - French language production in France photocopied agreements, 1965-1967 (Box 284, Folder 3712)
      - French language production in Switzerland photocopied agreement, 1966 (Box 284, Folder 3713)
      - German language stage rights typed agreement, 1995–2006 (Box 284, Folder 3714-3716)
      - German Educational Telecast typed agreement, 1972–1975 (Box 284, Folder 3717)
      - Greek language agreement, 2003–2008 (Box 285, Folder 3718-3719)
      - Greek language photocopied rights agreement, circa 1953 (Box 285, Folder 3720)
      - Hebrew language photocopied production contract, 1972 (Box 285, Folder 3721)
      - Hungarian language agreements
        - Artijus typed agreement, 1999 (Box 285, Folder 3722)
        - Artijus stage rights and agreement, 1989–1992 (Box 285, Folder 3723)
        - Hungarian copyright office agreement and correspondence, 1960–1967 (Box 285, Folder 3724)
      - Indonesian language United States Information Agency correspondence, 1989 August 28 (Box 285, Folder 3725)
      - Italian language agreements (Box 285)
        - Photocopied stage rights agreement, 1989 (Box 285, Folder 3726)
        - Stage production rights, 1964–1974 (Box 285, Folder 3727)
        - Arnoldo Mondadori Editore agreements, 1963–1977 (Box 285, Folder 3728-3729)
        - Concessionari Associate amateur rights, 2001 March 21 (Box 285, Folder 3730)
        - Our Town, The Skin of Our Teeth, and The Matchmaker agreements, 1974–1975 (Box 285, Folder 3731)
      - Japanese play license agreement, 1960 (Box 285, Folder 3732)
      - First class Japanese language stage rights, 1997–1998 (Box 285, Folder 3733)
      - Marathi language United States Information Agency agreement, 1966 January 10 (Box 285, Folder 3734)
      - Malagasy language agreements and correspondence, 1971–1978 (Box 285, Folder 3735)
      - Chinese language agreements, 1956–1986 (Box 285, Folder 3736)
      - Indian and Pakistani language agreements
        - Bengali language United States Information Agency agreement, 1964–1968 (Box 285, Folder 3737)
        - Telugu language United States Information Agency agreement, 1968 (Box 285, Folder 3738)
        - Urdu language United States Information Agency agreement, 1968 (Box 285, Folder 3739)
        - Gujarati langauge United States Information Agency agreement, 1965 November 8 (Box 285, Folder 3740)
      - Franklin publications multiple lanaguage translation permissions, 1990 April 24 (Box 285, Folder 3741)
      - Korean and Russian languages United States Information Agency photocopied permissions, 1969 (Box 285, Folder 3742)
      - Portuguese language agreements and rights
        - Brazilian production language rights, 1998 May 28 (Box 286, Folder 3743)
        - Stage rights in Brazil, 1989 November 10 (Box 286, Folder 3744)
        - Photocopied stage production agreement in Lisbon, Portugal, circa 1968 (Box 286, Folder 3745)
      - Romanian language photocopied production agreement, 1968 (Box 286, Folder 3746)
      - Russian language agreements, 1973–2008 (Box 286, Folder 3747-3748)
      - Scandinavian language typescript agreements
        - Finnish language typescript stage rights, 1978 (Box 286, Folder 3749)
        - First class language stage rights for Norway, Sweden, Denmark, and Iceland, 1976–1986 (Box 286, Folder 3750)
      - Franklin publications photocopied agreement and correspondence, circa 1953 (Box 286, Folder 3751)
      - Japanese and Korean language rights, 1957–1989 (Box 286, Folder 3752-3754)
      - Korean language agreements
        - Amateur rights agreement, 1999 March 29 (Box 286, Folder 3755)
        - Language rights, 2006 (Box 286, Folder 3756)
        - National Drama Company agreements, 2006–2007 (Box 286, Folder 3757)
      - Polish language materials
        - Language stage rights and amendment, 1997 (Box 286, Folder 3758)
        - Language agreement (2 copies), 2000 (Box 286, Folder 3759)
        - Language stage rights, 1993 (Box 286, Folder 3760)
        - First class stage rights, 1989 (Box 286, Folder 3761)
        - Photocopied production rights, 1972 (Box 286, Folder 3762)
        - First class production rights in Poland, 1966 (Box 287, Folder 3763)
        - First class copy agreement in Poland, 1962 (Box 287, Folder 3764)
          Agreement is signed by Thornton Wilder.
        - Production contract typescript and photocopy, 1957 (Box 287, Folder 3765)
      - Spanish language rights in Uruguay, 2001 (Box 287, Folder 3766)
      - Spanish language amateur production in Argentina play license agreement, 1993 (Box 287, Folder 3767)
      - Spanish language agreement in Argentina photocopy, 1977 (Box 287, Folder 3768)
      - Spanish language agreement in Argentina, undated (Box 287, Folder 3769)
      - Spanish language agreement in Spain, 1975 (Box 287, Folder 3770)
      - Yugoslavian agreements and correspondence, 1976 (Box 287, Folder 3771)
  - Charlotte Wilder materials, 1928–2009
    - Plutarch for Boys and Girls bound cover with loose and photocopied pages, undated (Box 288, Folder 3772)
    - "Of All Our Immemorial Past: 150 Years at Wheaton" pamphlet, 1985 (Box 288, Folder 3773)
    - Mental health typescripts and transcripts, undated (Box 288, Folder 3774)
      Includes photocopied correspondence from Amos to Janet as well as transcripts from the Wilder Records about Charlotte's health. Also includes correspondence from Janet Henle addressed to Isabel Wilder.
    - Mental illness notes, correspondence, and clippings, 1939–2008 (Box 288, Folder 3775)
      Includes notes and correspondence, both handwritten and photocopied, among family members including Amos Niven Wilder about Charlotte's mental illness. Also includes typescript chronologies, and newspaper articles.
    - Photocopied and handwritten personal histories, 1969–2009 (Box 288, Folder 3776)
      Also includes printed Wikipedia entries on various psychiatric facilites.
    - Union Trust account, 1978–1980 (Box 288, Folder 3777)
    - The Brattleboro Retreat materials, 1969–1972 (Box 288, Folder 3778)
    - South Oaks pyschiatric hospital correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 288, Folder 3779)
    - Gould Farm pamphlet and blank application, undated (Box 288, Folder 3780)
    - "Mount Holyoke Monthly" photocopy and request form, 2007 (Box 288, Folder 3781)
    - Wilder, Amos Parker correspondence, 1911–1915 (Box 288, Folder 3782-3784)
      Also includes photocopy typescript from the Wilder Records.
    - Wilder, Amos Niven outgoing correspondence, 1916–1951 (Box 288, Folder 3785-3786)
      Handwritten letters addressed to Charlotte and his parents.
    - Wilder, Amos Niven incoming correspondence, 1932–1966 (Box 288, Folder 3787)
    - Wilder, Amos Niven incoming correspondence photocopies, circa 1969 (Box 288, Folder 3788)
    - Arachne inscribed to Charlotte Wilder and printed poetry enclosures, 1928–1931 (Box 288, Folder 3789)
      Both the book and the two enclosed poems are written by Amos Niven Wilder.
    - Dakin, Janet Wilder outgoing correspondence, 1968–1980 (Box 289, Folder 3790-3801)
      Letters addressed to Janet from Charlotte, South Oaks, and the Union Trust Company.
    - Personal materials
      - Family correspondence and handwritten poetry, 1943–1950 (Box 409, Folder 5273)
        Correspondence addressed to family members including Amos Niven and Isabella.
      - General correspondence, 1949–1966 (Box 409, Folder 5274-5279)
        Charlotte's correspondence from the Long Island Home in Amityville, New York addressed to family members, friends and other contacts. Also includes Mildred Squires Titley's correspondence with Wilder family members on Charlotte's condition.
      - Incoming correspondence, 1950–1957 (Box 409, Folder 5280)
        Correspondence from family members including Catharine Dix, Catharine Kerlin, Isabel, and Amos Niven.
      - Wilder, Amos Niven and Catharine Kerlin correspondence, 1950–1954 (Box 409, Folder 5281)
      - Niven, Charlotte T. correspondence, 1918–1952 (Box 409, Folder 5282)
      - Outgoing correspondence, 1941 (Box 410, Folder 5283)
        Mostly addressed to Isabella Wilder.
      - Correspondence, 1942–1944 (Box 410, Folder 5284-5285)
        Includes typescript poems written by Charlotte Wilder.
      - Muchnie, Helen, 1944 (Box 410, Folder 5286)
        Correspondence between Helen, Isabel, and Janet.
      - Scott, Evelyn correspondence addressed to Amos Niven Wilder, 1948 (Box 410, Folder 5287)
      - Correspondence, 1936–1953 (Box 410, Folder 5288-5289)
      - " After Anger " poetry clipping, 1935 (Box 410, Folder 5290)
      - Hamilton, Edith, 1940 (Box 410, Folder 5291)
        Includes a photocopy of a letter from Janet to Amos and Catharine.
      - Wilder, Isabel correspondence addressed to Janet, 1942 (Box 410, Folder 5292)
      - General correspondence, 1941–1945 (Box 410, Folder 5293-5298)
        Includes third party correspondence either to or from Isabel concerning Charlotte.
      - Selected poems typescripts, Mortal Sequence photocopied fragments, and correspondence, 1971–2004 (Box 410, Folder 5299)
        Poems selected by Amos Niven Wilder to publication in a volume. Also includes Tappan's correspondence with Dr. Caroline Maun about this volume.
      - Photocopied typescripts, undated (Box 410, Folder 5300)
        Copies of Charlotte's poetry and writings.
      - Poetry and writings, 1924–1971 (Box 411, Folder 5301-5302)
        Includes Phases of the Moon book cover and related photocopies. Also includes Poetry: A Magazine of Verse from 1924, 1932, and 1936.
      - Phases of the Moon research report, 2010 (Box 411, Folder 5303)
        Research report conducted by Thomson Reuters on behalf of Tappan Wilder on a search for the U.S. Copyright Registration/ Renewal of Phases of the Moon.
      - Wilder, Charlotte obituary clipping, chronology, trust agreement, and related correspondence, 1966–1980 (Box 411, Folder 5304)
      - Photocopied correspondence from Smith College archives, 1994 (Box 411, Folder 5305)
        Includes Tappan Wilder's photocopy request, photocopied correspondence, a list of common correspondents of Charlotte Wilder's, and Tappan's correspondence with Betsy Harries.
      - Wilder, Catharine Dix and Tappan correspondence, 1951–1988 (Box 411, Folder 5306)
        Dixie and Tappy's correspondence addressed to Charlotte, as well as letters addressed to Janet, letters from Amos Niven Wilder addressed to Tappy and Amos Todd
      - Fragments, undated (Box 411, Folder 5307)
        Includes a fragment written in Amos Niven's hand and A Mortal Sequence clipping.
      - Wilder, Isabel correspondence addressed to Amos Niven, circa 1918 (Box 411, Folder 5308)
  - Amos Niven Wilder materials, 1914–2010
    - Ecumenical Insitute materials and writings, 1963; undated (Box 290, Folder 3802)
      Includes handwritten lecture notes and lecture typescripts of other professors.
    - World Council of Churches materials, 1967–1980 (Box 290, Folder 3803-3804)
    - "The Fundamentals of Christianity" by Charles Foster Kent, 1925 (Box 290, Folder 3805)
    - New England Hermeneutics Group materials, 1965–1967 (Box 290, Folder 3806-3807)
    - Lewis, Wilmarth "Lefty" S. correspondence and clippings, 1969–1979 (Box 290, Folder 3808)
    - Yu, Anthony correspondence and clippings, 1978–1983 (Box 290, Folder 3809)
      Includes correspondence, clippings, book plates, library acquisitions, and writings
    - Jeffers, Robinson typescript and photocopied letter copy, undated (Box 290, Folder 3810)
    - Harvard Divinity School materials, 1999–2004 (Box 290, Folder 3811)
    - Biographical materials, 1935–1999 (Box 290, Folder 3812-3813, Box 122, Folder 1692)
      The second folder contains condolence letters sent to the Wilder family after Amos's death in 1993. The third folder contains an oversize photograph of the Yale Class of 1917 reuniting in 1977.
    - Wilder, Amos Tappan correspondence, 1989–1991 (Box 290, Folder 3814)
      Letters addressed both to Amos Tappan and Catharine Kerlin.
    - General correspondence, 1940–1988 (Box 290, Folder 3815)
    - Memorial service materials, 1993 (Box 290, Folder 3816)
    - Wilder typescript and photocopied records
      - Inventory of family and personal records, undated (Box 290, Folder 3817)
      - Autobiographical writings, undated (Box 290, Folder 3818)
      - Wilder, Thornton correspondence, undated (Box 290, Folder 3819)
        Photocopied correspondence from July 1915 to September 1916.
      - Wilder, Amos Parker correspondence, undated (Box 290, Folder 3820)
        Typescript copies of correspondence from May to November 1918.
      - Stanley, Blanche description, undated (Box 290, Folder 3821)
        Typescript reflections on Amos's time spent with Blanche Stanley in 1919.
      - Brussels, Munich, and Oxford typescript writings, undated (Box 290, Folder 3822)
        Typescript reflections on Amos's time in Brussels, Munich, and Oxford from 1920 to 1922.
      - Family correspondence, undated (Box 290, Folder 3823)
        Typescript letters from Amos's parents in 1922.
      - Stokes, Anson Phelps, undated (Box 290, Folder 3824)
        Typescript letters from Ansons Phelps Stokes.
      - Niven, Charlotte T., undated (Box 290, Folder 3825)
        Typescript and photocopy letter from Charlotte T. Niven from 1922.
      - Wilder, Isabel, undated (Box 290, Folder 3826)
        Typescript and photocopy letter from Isabel Wilder dated 1923.
      - North Conway, Hamilton College, and Andover Newton writings, undated (Box 290, Folder 3827)
        Typescript writings from 1925-1931.
      - Patchen, Kenneth, undated (Box 290, Folder 3828)
        Typescript writings from 1934.
      - Daniel Evans retirement writing, undated (Box 290, Folder 3829)
        Typescript writing from circa 1939.
      - Addresses and sermons record, undated (Box 290, Folder 3830)
        Handwritten and photocopy of a list of addresses and sermons Amos gave from 1945 to 1946.
      - University of Frankfurt writings, undated (Box 290, Folder 3831)
      - Wilder, Charlotte's correspondence to Amos Parker and Amos Niven, undated (Box 290, Folder 3832)
        Typescript and photocopy of Charlotte's letters to her father and brother between 1911 and 1914.
      - Mortal Sequences review by William Rose Benet, undated (Box 290, Folder 3833)
        Photocopy review written in 1936.
      - Wilder, Charlotte correspondence to Amos Niven, undated (Box 290, Folder 3834)
        Typescript and photocopy of correspondence written in 1939
      - Wilder, Amos Parker correspondence to Amos Niven, undated (Box 290, Folder 3835)
        Typescript and photocopy of letter in 1916.
      - Deschamps, Jules notes, undated (Box 290, Folder 3836)
      - Wilder, Isabella poetry, undated (Box 290, Folder 3837)
        Typescript and photocopy of poetry written by Isabella Wilder.
      - Maine Wilder relatives, undated (Box 290, Folder 3838)
        Typescript and photocopies from 1932 writings. Also includes a photocopy of Wilder Hobson's Memorial Service program.
      - Peabody, Harry correspondence, undated (Box 290, Folder 3839)
        Photocopied correspondence from 1922.
      - Mother of Four reviews, undated (Box 291, Folder 3840)
        Typescript and photocopied reviews from 1932-1948.
      - "Items" including photocopied and typescript timelines, undated (Box 291, Folder 3841)
      - Family bibliography typescript, 1977–1987 (Box 291, Folder 3842)
    - Honors and special events clippings, lists, and correspondence, 1965–1993 (Box 291, Folder 3843-3844)
      Includes a list of guests to a wedding, Wilbur Cross medal ceremony materials, and clippings.
    - Society for the Arts, Religion, and Contemporary Culture, Inc. materials, 1969–2008 (Box 291, Folder 3845)
    - Battle- Retrospect typescript photocopy and The Last Battle typescript, undated (Box 291, Folder 3846)
    - Amos Wilder Lecture in Scripture and Literary Arts materials, 1994–2006 (Box 291, Folder 3847)
    - "Yale. June, 1920" poem set to music correspondence, 2006 December 19 (Box 291, Folder 3848)
    - Transcribed Wilder family correspondence, circa 1969 (Box 291, Folder 3849-3850)
    - Yale documents and photocopied articles, circa 1919-1926 (Box 291, Folder 3851)
      Includes correspondence from The Elizabethan Club, University Extension Delegacy ticket, a program from Amos's oridination, and photocopied articles written by Amos during his time at Yale.
    - Wilder-Niven family biography notes, circa 1976 (Box 291, Folder 3852)
      Includes photocopied and original clippings concerning Amos Niven, Amos Parker, Janet Wilder Dakin, and other Wilder family members.
    - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America and Annunity Funds for Ministers materials, 1950-1985 (Box 291, Folder 3853)
    - Library photocopied and handwritten notes, circa 1971-1985 (Box 291, Folder 3854-3855)
    - Andover- Harvard Theological Library book and materials records and correspondence, 1979–2008 (Box 291, Folder 3856)
    - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library receipts of gifts, 1968–1999 (Box 291, Folder 3857)
    - Blue Hill, Maine writings and related materials, 1934–1978 (Box 292, Folder 3858-3859)
      Includes photographs of Catharine Dix and Amos Tappan, typescript and photocopies of "Annals of a Sylvan Retreat", and other writings.
    - Photocopied and original off print writings, 1943–1999 (Box 292, Folder 3860-3861)
    - Theological printed and typescript writings, 1962–1990 (Box 292, Folder 3862)
    - Printed, handwritten, and photocopied poems, circa 1920-1958 (Box 292, Folder 3863-3864)
    - Printed, typescript, and handwritten poems, 1971–2005 (Box 292, Folder 3865)
      Includes multiple copies of a script for a recording for Modern Poetry Room Lamont.
    - Book reviews written by Amos Niven Wilder, 1945–1953 (Box 292, Folder 3866)
    - Photocopied and original copies of reviews of Amos Niven Wilder's books, circa 1953-1992 (Box 292, Folder 3867-3868)
    - Bibliography of Biblical studies, circa 1995 (Box 292, Folder 3869)
    - List of publications and Vita, undated (Box 292, Folder 3870)
      Lists of Amos Niven Wilder's publications.
    - Biographical materials, 1911–1986 (Box 293, Folder 3871-3872)
      Includes an autobiographical typescript, clippings, handwritten writings, information about Amos's health, and Harvard materials.
    - "Amos Wilder Who Knew Him?" written by Joe Bassett, 2009–2010 (Box 293, Folder 3873)
    - Ordination service program, 1926 February 9 (Box 293, Folder 3874)
      Includes a photocopied letter addressed to Tappan Wilder.
    - Andover-Newton photocopied materials, undated (Box 293, Folder 3875)
      Includes correspondence addressed to President Everett C. Herrick, notes, appications, and a general catalog.
    - Yale Divinity School photocopied records, 1999 (Box 293, Folder 3876)
      Records of Amos's time as a student including his application to the school.
    - Senior Thesis, undated (Box 293, Folder 3877)
    - Harvard Divinity School Bulletin photocopy, circa 1993 (Box 293, Folder 3878)
      The article is about Armageddon Revisited.
    - White, Katharine S. photocopied correspondence, 1999 (Box 293, Folder 3879)
    - Handwritten and photocopied sermons and addresses, circa 1944 (Box 293, Folder 3880)
      Includes clippings and a photocopied records of sermons given between 1945 and 1947.
    - "Christianity and Crisis" printed materials, 1991 (Box 293, Folder 3881)
    - Wilder family postcards, 1916–1935 (Box 293, Folder 3882-3885)
      Includes both blank and handwritten postcards.
    - Personal photographs, 1948–1992 (Box 293, Folder 3886-3887)
      The second folder includes a list of photographs developed by Amos.
    - Berlin travel authorization documents, 1953 (Box 293, Folder 3888)
    - Chicago house materials, 1928–1953 (Box 293, Folder 3889-3890)
      Leases, payments, and other documentation relating to the house the Wilders owned in Chicago.
    - Cambridge house materials, 1954–1968 (Box 293, Folder 3891-3892)
      Includes agreements, correspondence, and blueprints.
    - Boston University Scripture and Literary Arts lecture photocopied article and correspondence, 2006–2007 (Box 293, Folder 3893)
    - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America and College Retirement Equities Fund materials, 1933–1963 (Box 294, Folder 3894)
    - Publication agreements, 1984–2007 (Box 294, Folder 3895)
    - Vita, undated (Box 294, Folder 3896)
      Typescript and photocopies of Amos's circulum vita.
    - Photocopied Frank Kermode correspondence, 1992 (Box 294, Folder 3897)
      Also includes typescript correspondence addressed to Amos Tappan.
    - Memorial service materials, circa 1993 (Box 294, Folder 3898-3899)
      Includes programs, photocopied and handwritten notes, and clippings.
    - Obituary clippings, photocopied clippings, typescript and correspondence, 1993–1994 (Box 294, Folder 3900-3901)
    - Writings
      - Unidentified correspondence, 1923 April 24 (Box 294, Folder 3902)
      - "Gerald Manley Hopkins" photocopy with inscription to Amos from Charlotte, undated (Box 294, Folder 3903)
      - "The Chant of Creation" printed copy, 1938 (Box 294, Folder 3904)
      - "Personality and the Protestant Tradition", "The Harvard Advocate", and book review of "Last Poems and Plays", 1940 (Box 294, Folder 3905)
      - "Voices of Our Day", "The Congress Papers", and Archibald MacLeish correspondence, 1941 (Box 294, Folder 3906)
      - "War-Time Leafelet of St. John's Church", 1942 (Box 294, Folder 3907)